CURRICULUM VITAE

Friday, 04-03-2020



EDUCATION

Bachelor in Computer Engineering

Pulchowk Campus, IOE, Tribhuvan University 2012 - 2016

Aggregate Score: 70.56% (First Division)

+2 Science

SOS Hermann Gmeiner HSS, HSEB

2010 - 2012

Aggregate Score: 79.20% (Distinction)

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python,

JavaScript, C, C++

Web Frameworks: Django, Django Rest

Framework

Frontend: ReactJS, React Native, jQuery,

HTML, CSS

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Sqlite

Server: AWS, Digital Ocean

Data Science: Matlab, Octave, Numpy

Other: Docker, GraphQL, Bash

ANISH SHRESTHA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Phone: (977) 9860 140468 | **Email:** anish.shrestha5432@gmail.com

Address: Madhyapur Thimi, Bhaktapur, Nepal, 44811 | Web: annshress.github.io

ABOUT ME

I'm a 25 years old Full Stack Developer currently based in Nepal. I am keen about everything that has to do with Python, Web design & development and Data Science. I feel a true devotion to become a Python Wizard. I am a good team player and work independently and directly with clients as well.

WORK EXPERIENCE

JAN 2020 - ongoing

Full Stack Developer | Remote

Freelance

I am active in Upwork and Fiverr. My most recent achievement is a CRM application for a German client. I reduced administration communication costs and improved customer information retrieval.

OCT 2018 - DEC 2019

Full Stack Developer | Remote

Unified Private Limited, Florida, US

I collaboratively built a B2C application called Workplace. With TDD and Agile methodologies, we curtailed business weight of joining incongruous domain applications by pre-assembling them, while ensuring efficient individual and bulk profit analysis.

OCT 2016 - JAN 2019

Software Developer | Kathmandu

Infiniahub Private Limited, Kathmandu, Nepal

As a Juvenile, I learned the most here. I created InfiniaStores for small-medium businesses where central agent can have complete control over several branches while reducing the overhead of order management and providing expense analysis. I increased Test Coverage by 30% for InfiniaBiz to increase resiliency of real-time communication between buying and selling agents.

EXTRA COURSERS

Introduction to Deep Learning

Instructors: Alexender Panin et al., NRU Higher School of Economics, Coursera

Machine Learning

Instructors: Andrew Ng, Stanford University, Coursera

Computational Methods for Data Analysis

Instructors: Nathan Kutz, University of Washington, Coursera

CERTIFICATES

GIS and Remote Sensing

Resource Himalaya Foundation, Sanepa

Volunteering and Participation

LOCUS (National Technological Fest)

Stipend based on Merit

Institute of Engineering

MEMBERSHIP

Nepal Engineering Council

PROJECTS

Automated Facial Expression Analysis and Recognition (Major)

Using publicly available datasets like JAFFE, we applied Principal Component Analysis and Local Binary Patterns like feature extractors to feed into Support Vector Machine and Convolutional Neural Network classifiers. We were able to yield analytical and comparative study between applied methods.

Football Result Predictor (Minor)

We successfully executed our first Machine Learning project to produce a comparative analysis on techniques like Back Propagation Neural Network, KNN, Naive Bayes to predict results of games of English Premier League based on past results.